# MERON **ASFAW**

5805 Andros Ct. #3, San Diego, CA 92115 · (415) 416-5759

Named.adulis@gmail.com · https://www.linkedin.com/in/masfaw/

Entrepreneur, software & hardware engineer focusing on efficient code solving problems. Also experienced in math & computer science tutoring. Speak 4 languages including English and some Spanish. Have traveled and lived more than 10 counties around the world. I can easily adapt and adjust to a multi-cultural environment.

### **EXPERIENCE**

SEPTEMBER 2019 – JUNE 2021 RTL & FPGA ENGINEER, QUALCOMM

• Encryption & Decryption Processor 9-bit ISA: I implemented and designed ISA, and Machine Code/Compiler that can encrypt/decrypt with pre-determined 9 LFSR Parity to any ASCII string length 49 b/n (0x20) and (0x9f).

Technology Used: C/C++, Python, SystemVerilog, ModelSim & Quartus Prime

• Error Correction FPGA: Forward error correction block coder/transmitter: Given a series of fifteen 11-bit message blocks in data mem[0:29], generate the corresponding 16-bit (2-byte) encoded versions and store these in data mem[30:59]. I built a data memory, a register file (cache), an ALU, a program counter, an instruction (machine code) memory, and some way to parse my instructions into register file address pointers, ALU instructions, and register file and data memory write enables. All muxes with control bits, as well.

Technology Used: C/C++, Python, SystemVerilog, ModelSim, Quartus Prime, Linux, Markup, GitHub

JUNE 2018 – JUNE 2019 SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TUSIMPLE

• Compress & Uncompress: I built a project involves coding executables files to compress & uncompressing with C/C++ in Linux environment that implement Huffman Coding algorithm.

Technology Used: C/C++, Linux, Python, Markup, GitHub

### **EDUCATION**

SEPTEMBER 2015 – JUNE 2018 A.S. COMPUTER SCIENCE, LANEY COLLEGE

GPA: 3.6

SEPTEMBER 2018 – JUNE 2022

B.S. COMPUTER ENGINNER, UNIVERSITY OF CALICALIFORNIA, SAN DIEGO

GPA: 3.0

#### **SKILLS**

- C/C++/Java/Python/Linux (6 years)
- SystemVerilog/ModelSim/Quartus (3 years)
- MATLAB/Mathcad/OrCAD (1 years)
- JavaScript/HTML/C# (1 year)

## **ACTIVITIES**

Surf the Ocean waves, weight workout at the gym, hike/camp/cock climb, cook Ethiopian Food